Jorge Basilio

New Brunswick, NJ 08901 | Cell - (732) 908-6630 | Email | GitHub | LinkedIn

Portfolio Website: https://jorgebasilio.tech

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Java (Spring - Boot), Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript-based programming. Passionate about code and strong skills include working in a team-oriented setting, leadership skills, problem solving, reliability, adaptability, with open-mind and willing to learn anything.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java (Spring boot), Ruby on Rails, Python (Django), JavaScript, React, TypeScript, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Movie-Nuggets - Frontend | Backend | Demo

An IMDB type of application that allows the user to watch movie trailers and leave reviews.

Back-End: Java (Spring boot), Front-End: React with Material UI and Bootstrap

MongoDB: Populates the movies from server and allows user to create reviews.

Coffee-Stand – Frontend | Demo

A beautiful landing page for a coffee delivery company using mostly HTML and CSS. The application demonstrates my understanding of styling a beautiful website.

EDUCATION

Western Governors University (Bachelor's in Science - BS, Computer Science) May 2022 – June 2023

Flatiron Coding Bootcamp (Immersive Software Engineering – Manhattan NY) Jan 2020 – Jun 2020 Cohort

Southern New Hampshire University (Computer Science – No degree) Jan 2019 - August 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apprentice Now - Application Development Apprenticeship (Java Intensive – Remote) July 2022 - Sept 2022 Cohort

- 8 Week intensive coding course, that show student's computer fundamentals, and how to program in Java Full stack.
- Frontend (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Angular)
- Backend (Java, Spring boot)
- Database (MySql, MongoDB)

RWJBH Hospital, New Brunswick, NJ - Lead Security Officer (Shift Supervisor) November 11, 2018 – July 2022

- Security shift supervisor of a Level One Trauma Center
- Liaison for senior leadership team and provide assistance with any supply shortages, any internal conflicts, and exchange of information.
- Oversee day to day operations and scheduling for a team of 60 officers.
- Conduct investigations and submit reports regarding hospital activity on behalf of the security team.
- Work in conjunction with the local police department for major incidents

New Brunswick Police Department- Auxiliary Police officer

June 12th, 2013 - August 2015

- Perform uniform foot patrol to provide necessary police presence at specific events.
- Assist in traffic and crowd control during specific details and events.
- Assist Service members in determining the community's policing and safety concerns.

RWJBH Hospital, New Brunswick, NJ - Security officer

November 11, 2012 – November 2018

- Secure facility and building associates by patrolling premises; monitoring camera equipment; inspecting buildings, machinery, and entry & exit points.
- Completes detailed reports by recording observations, gathering necessary information, and relaying occurrences to proper authorities.
- Respond in a timely manner to both routine and emergency calls.
- Check for unsafe conditions, security hazards, potential risks, security violations, and unauthorized persons on hospital property.
- Dispatch calls out to police and law enforcement officers when the situation requires.
- Assist medical staff with any patient concerns and issues.
- Follow up on reports of theft, workplace violence and other incidents.
- Control the flow of traffic and ensure vehicles are not a hindrance to hospital operations.

CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

After Graduation - ITIL-4 Foundations Certification Software Engineering certification from Flatiron Coding Bootcamp (2020)